Roni Sarig Collection, 1984-2007, bulk 2000-2007 SC 148
Archives of African American Music and Culture
- 2. Interviews (audio), undated; 40 audio recordings
  - 2.1. Interviews conducted by Roni Sarig, undated; 34 Audio Files
    - Interviews with Lil Ru, Pastor Troy, and the Filthy Boys, undated; CASS 2203; Sarig, Roni (Writer on music); 1 Audiocassette: digital + 1 index
      Pastor Troy, Lil Ru and Filthy Boys interviewed by Rhonda Baraka.
      Atlanta rapper and record producer Pastor Troy talks with Rhonda Baraka about his career in the hip hop industry, his early life, why he chose this particular direction for his musical career, and some of his major influences; his new album "We Ready (I Declare War)," the inspirations for the songs and Timbaland's role as the producer; his goals for the future and eventual retirement. Rhonda Baraka interviews Lil Ru (aka Sylvester Samuels), a 15-year-old rapper from South Carolina, about his upcoming debut album, "Wild Child," giving some insight into the influences and deeper meanings of the songs; his goals for his career and what the changing environment in the rap industry means for his music. Rhonda Baraka interviews the Filthy Boys, a rap duo from North Carolina, about their upcoming album, their artistic vision, the current state of the rap music industry, and their future career goals.
    - Interviews with ESG and KLC, undated; CASS 2205; Sarig, Roni (Writer on music); 1 Audiocassette: digital + 1 index
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/484z50j207
      Members of the group ESG and producer KLC interviewed by Roni Sarig, author of the book, The Third Coast: Outkast, Timbaland, and How Hip Hop Became a Southern Thing.
      The microphone is not working for ESG, so we can only hear Sarig asking questions. DJ, drummer, and record producer KLC (aka Craig Stephen Lawson) talks about his early life and education, how he got into music, working with Slim Thug, relationship to Screwed Up Click, his work in the music industry, his unreleased albums, time spent in jail, the culture of drinking lean, rivalries between North and South Houston, and his plans for the future.
    - Interviews with DJ Chill and Lil' Troy, undated; CASS 2206; Sarig, Roni (Writer on music); 1 Audiocassette: digital + 1 index
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/188158cm9g
      Houston artists DJ Chill and Lil' Troy interviewed by Roni Sarig, author of the book, The Third Coast: Outkast, Timbaland, and How Hip Hop Became a Southern Thing.
      (The beginning of this interview starts on Side B of this tape) Troy talks about working with Scarface, giving the suburban boy a persona fitting of the lyrics Troy was writing for him; Scarface leaving and joining with Geto Boys; how Troy became a solo artist but went to prison right after his debut album went platinum; 9/11 and its effect on his second album, which released on the same day; and Troy's influence on the Houston music scene. Chill details his early interest in collecting and mixing records; how he was introduced to mixing and producing music with the help of his father who owned a studio; his childhood friend DJ Screw and Screw's popularity, unique sound mixing, and influence. Sarig's interview of Troy begins with Troy explaining his place in the hip hop scene, how Scarface dropped his name from his track, his younger years and his introduction to music through his family.
    - Interviews with Luke Campbell and MC A.D.E., undated; CASS 2207; Sarig, Roni (Writer on music); 1 Audiocassette: digital + 1 index
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/r074850r7p
      Florida artists and producers Luke Campbell and M.C. A.D.E. interviewed by Roni Sarig, author of the book, The Third Coast: Outkast, Timbaland, and How Hip Hop Became a Southern Thing.
      Roni Sarig and Luke (aka Luther Roderick Campbell) talk about Luke's childhood and his inspiration for making music; his first DJ group, the equipment they used, types of music they performed and venues; his early involvement with 2 Live Crew, joining the group, and helping them become a much bigger name in the music industry, and legal problems resulting from their obscene lyrics; why 2 Live Crew got back together, problems with their contract, filing for bankruptcy, and people trying to steal Luke's catalogue. Sarig and M.C. A.D.E. talk about his childhood, how he got involved with music at an early age through his father's record store; how he got to produce M.C. Chief's "Beef Box" (1984), which was a major commercial success; 4 Sight Records, Miami Bass, and some of the projects he produced for various artists.
    - Interviews with J Dogg, C-Murder, and John Abbey, undated; CASS 2209; Sarig, Roni (Writer on music); 1 Audiocassette: digital + 1 index
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/q27z60f486
      John "J-Dogg" Shaw, C-Murder, and John Abbey are interviewed by Roni Sarig, author of the book, The Third Coast: Outkast, Timbaland, and How Hip Hop Became a Southern Thing.
      John "J-Dogg" Shaw and Roni Sarig continue their discussion of the Memphis rap scene; the city's connection to and perception of music from other southern cities including New Orleans, Jackson, and Atlanta; Memphis rappers such as Gangsta Pat and 8Ball & MJG that moved away from Memphis to seek success; interpersonal problems with Three 6 Mafia and other rappers, as well as the recent successes of Playa Fly and Yo Gotti; and the role of Ichiban Records and Select-O-Hits. C-Murder (aka Corey Miller) discusses rap and hip-hop in New Orleans; his early musical influences as well as his family, primarily Master P and Silkk; his time in prison, his musical style, and upcoming album. John Abbey of Ichiban Records discusses hip-hop and rap in Atlanta, his connection to the blues and soul scene, the start of Ichiban Records, the first rap music Abbey remembers hearing in Atlanta, as well as some of the artists signed on Ichiban, including MC Breed and 95 South. (Continued on cass 2199).
  - 2.2. Interviews conducted by others, undated; 6 Audio Files
    - Interviews with Bonecrusher and Unknown Interviewees [by Rhonda Baraka?], undated; CASS 2180; 1 Audiocassette: digital + 1 index
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/682x11zh8f
      Bonecrusher and various unknowns interviewed by Rhonda Baraka
      Bonecrusher talks about how he got started, then moving on to discussing his hit song "Never Scared" and what made it popular. They then discuss what would become the AttenCHUN! before finishing the interview by talking about Bonecrusher's future plans. Baraka talks to Unknown (an "entertainment lawyer"?) about the entertainment business in the South/ Atlanta in particular. Baraka talks to Unknown from CMJ about Atlanta as a center for music and technology in the Southeast. Baraka interviews Unknown, talking about Earth Challenge Festival, events, concerts and fundraising focusing on health and environmental awareness in Montana. Baraka interviews Unknown, talking about Earth Challenge Festival, events, concerts and fundraising focusing on health and environmental awareness in Montana. An unknown executive discusses the processes around labels signing bands in Atlanta. Unknown clarifies the roles of various positions, such as A&R's. He also talks about a conference called Atlantis that he is helping put together. Unknown artists talks about her time at the conference Atlantis. Unknown explains the benefits that the conference brings to participants as well as the city of Atlanta. Unknown label executive talks about his time working at CMJ.
    - Interviews about Lisa Lopes and American Urban Radio Networks [by Rhonda Baraka?], undated; CASS 2192; 1 Audiocassette: digital + 1 index
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/5644753m8z
      Rhonda Baraka interviews several unidentified men and women about Lisa Lopes and American Urban Radio Networks.
      Baraka and unidentified man discuss the recent death of Lisa Lopes, her public image and the affects her death will have on TLC. Unidentified man talks about the recent death of Lisa Lopes from a car crash. They discuss her charity work in Honduras and the affects her death will have on TLC. Unidentified woman talks about her album and speaks on balancing it in a way that allows her to communicate the things she wants, reaching as many people as possible. She talks about writing music, her mom's view on her career and possibilities outside of music. Unidentified person describes working with unidentified artist. Unidentified man from American Urban Radio Networks speaks to Baraka about the network's anniversary, past history, the challenges AURN has faced and where it is headed in the future. E. J. "Jay" Williams Jr., President of American Urban Radio Networks speaks to Baraka about AURN, history of Mutual Black Network and Sheridan Broadcasting, evolution of AURN and changes over time, the successes the network achieved and plans for the future.
    - Interviews with Amos Larkins and Clarence "Blowfly" Reid [by Rhonda Baraka?], undated; CASS 2195; 1 Audiocassette: digital + 1 index
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/k81j52xc92
      Miami artists Amos Larkins and Clarence "Blowfly" Reid are interviewed by Roni Sarig, author of the book, The Third Coast: Outkast, Timbaland, and How Hip Hop Became a Southern Thing.
      Amos Larkins discusses his role in the development of the Miami Bass sound, the groups he produced including Krush 2, his history in music production in the 1980s, working in the Bee Gee's studio at night, how he accidentally invented the Miami Bass sound while mixing and its positive reception, his break from music, and his return to the industry producing techno and jazz music. Clarence "Blowfly" Reid, songwriter, producer, and rapper, his propensity to create parodies of clean songs, turning them "dirty' or explicit; explains his history with Deep City Records and his signing of Betty Wright; moving to Miami, meeting Henry Stone and working for TK Records.
    - Interviews with Baby D, Big Oomp, Lil C, Tim Kelley, Bob Robinson and Unidentified person [by Rhonda Baraka?], undated; CASS 2198; 1 Audiocassette: digital + 1 index
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/r074850r6c
      Rhonda Baraka interviews Atlanta-based rappers Baby D, Big Oomp, and Lil C; Atlanta-based songwriter-producers Tim Kelley and Bob Robinson (aka Funktwons); and unidentified RCA executive.
      Baby D, Big Oomp, and Lil C discuss with Baraka the reasons why they are doing a record label deal with Epic, other artists they are working with, and the specifics of the deal between Epic and Big Oomp. They also discuss the origin of Big Oomp Records, Big Oomp Enterprises and their ongoing and upcoming projects. Tim, Kelly and Bob Robinson explain their process of finding artists with star potential. Unidentified marketing executive talks to Baraka about past marketing experiences at corporations such as Kraft and Pepsi, her job description at RCA Records, her first project at the label, and whether or not companies prefer specific genres of artists, or artists with crossover appeal.
    - Interviews with Lil' Jon, Sloan Molot and Vincent Phillips [by Rhonda Baraka?], undated; CASS 2202; 1 Audiocassette: digital + 1 index
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/k81j52xd0j
      Lil' Jon, Sloan Molot and Vincent Phillips interviewed by Rhonda Baraka about Lil' Jon's career.
      In this phone interview, Baraka and Lil' Jon discuss his knowledge of the industry, his upcoming marketing plans, and his successes. Sloane Molot, an executive at Warner Bros., discusses various technical aspects of Lil' Jon's career. Baraka and Vince Phillips, an executive at Black Market Entertainment (BME), discuss Lil' Jon's popularity, as well as that of crunk music in general, and how his vision and persona have remained the same throughout his career. Baraka and Lil' Jon discuss his early career and popularity (discussion continues on Side A of this cassette).
    - Interviews with Crime Mob and Lil' Romeo [by Rhonda Baraka?], undated; CASS 2208; 1 Audiocassette: digital + 1 index
      https://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/media/q47r66k94v
      Members of Crime Mob and Lil' Romeo interviewed by Rhonda Baraka.
      Baraka talks with members of the Atlanta group Crime Mob about how they got their start as musicians, how they met, the group's sound, their upcoming album and single "Knuck If You Buck," and their long term plans. Baraka talks with rapper Lil' Romeo about his upcoming album, Romeoland, including the songs "My Cinderella," "Missin' You," "Bobblehead," and "My Girlfriend." They also discuss his work-life balance and long-term goals.